Guide to the News Service Scrapbook collection, 1916-1944
Duke University. University Archives
News Service Scrapbook collection 1916-1944
Duke University. University Archives
Duke University. Office of News and Communication.
15.9 linear feet Extent: 23 Items
The mission of the Duke News Service is to inform the public and the university community about research, programs, and events at Duke; to increase public understanding and appreciation of scholarly contributions made by Duke's faculty and the work of its other employees and students; and to provide media relations and consultative services to faculty and administrators. The collection includes News Service scrapbooks for both Trinity College and Duke University. General interest and sports news make up the bulk of the clippings. The collection ranges in date from 1916-1944.
RL.01740
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
Provenance
The News Service Scrapbook collection were received by the University Archives as a transfer in 1989.
Historical Note
The mission of the Duke News Service is to inform the public and the university community about research, programs, and events at Duke; to increase public understanding and appreciation of scholarly contributions made by Duke's faculty and the work of its other employees and students; and to provide media relations and consultative services to faculty and administrators. The Duke News Service works closely with local, national, and international news media, including newspapers, radio and television, magazines, wire services and syndicates.
Collection Overview
The collection includes News Service scrapbooks for both Trinity College and Duke University. General interest and sports news make up the bulk of the clippings. Among the major subjects are student life and traditions, the building of the university, and news of the major and minor sports. Some of the clippings relate to obscure organizations at Duke, including the Cat's Head Club. In addition to clippings are news releases, programs and correspondence. Scrapbooks 8-21 contain clippings only. According to a handwritten note on the clippings envelope in box 11, scrapbook 22 was dismantled in 1989. The clippings envelope contains articles related to the last illness, death and burial of President Few. The collection ranges in date from 1916-1944.
Collection Arrangement
Some of the scrapbooks were unhinged in the box. The pages were foldered, keeping the original order. Many pages and clippings are brittle and should be handled with care.
Subject Headings
Duke University. News Service.; Duke University. History -- 20th century; Duke University -- Administration.; Duke University -- Alumni and alumnae.; Duke University -- Faculty.; Duke University -- Students.; Duke University -- Students -- Societies, etc; Duke University -- Athletics; Duke University -- Buildings -- History -- 20th century; Trinity College (Durham, N.C.). History -- 20th century; Trinity College (Durham, N.C.)--Administration; Trinity College (Durham, N.C.)--Alumni and alumnae; Trinity College (Durham, N.C.). Library; Trinity College (Durham, N.C.)--Sports; Trinity College (Durham, N.C.)--Students -- Societies, etc
Related Material
News Service Biographical Files, 1960-2004
University Archives, Duke University.
News Service Subject Files, 1930-ongoing.
University Archives, Duke University.
Duke University Archives Scrapbook collection, 1916-ongoing.
University Archives, Duke University.
Biographical Reference Collection, 1972-2004.
University Archives, Duke University.
Building Reference Collection, 1972-2004.
University Archives, Duke University.
Contents of Collection
- Container List, 12 Boxes
  - Scrapbook 1 1916 September-1917 August (Box 1)
    Contains news releases, correspondence, a program from the 22nd Annual Meeting of the Association of Colleges and Secondary Schools of the Southern States which was held at Trinity College, commencement programs, a Trinity Songs program marking the quarter-centennial year of Trinity College in Durham, and clippings.
  - Scrapbook 2 1917 September [August]-1918 June
    Contains largely clippings, some correspondence, and various programs. Of note is a pamphlet from the War Department entitled "Military Training at Trinity College" and a Student Army Training Corps (SATC) grade card and course program brochure.
  - Scrapbook 3 1919 September-1920 June
    Contains largely clippings, a statement to the United Chapters of Phi Beta Kappa regarding Trinity College's application, correspondence and various programs.
  - Scrapbook 4 1920 September-1922 May (Box 2)
    Contains clippings and various programs.
  - Scrapbook 5 1921 September-1922 January
    Contains clippings.
  - Scrapbook 6 1923 September-November
  - Scrapbook 7 1923 November-1924 January (Box 3)
    Contains clippings and a list of Trinity students who died in the World War I.
  - Scrapbook 8 1924 February-March
  - Scrapbook 9 1924 March-June
  - Scrapbook 10 1922 May-1924 November (Box 4)
  - Scrapbook 11 1924-1925
    Contains clippings about The Duke Endowment.
  - Scrapbook 12 1925 January-December
  - Scrapbook 13 1926 January-December (Box 5)
  - Scrapbook 14 1927 January-September (Box 6)
  - Scrapbook 15 1927 October-December (Box 7)
  - Scrapbook 16 1928 January-May (Box 8)
  - Scrapbook 17 1928 June-December (Box 9)
  - Scrapbook 19 1930 July-1935 July (Box 10)
  - Scrapbook 18 1929 January-February (Box 11)
  - Scrapbook 20 1931 January
  - Scrapbook 21 1938 November-1939 January
  - Clippings Envelope [formerly scrapbook 22] 1940 October
  - Scrapbook 23 1944 February (Box 12)
    Clippings regarding Assistant Secretary of State A.A. Berle Jr.'s speaking engagement at Duke University February 7, 1944.